Let's talk about tailoring the project management processes you already know that you don't have to
use every process on every project.
But then we also have to make a determination as to what depth we should utilize the processes that
are selected and then we can even tailor those processes to fit the type of projects that we're managing
or our organization or what's most important to us in our project or endeavor.
So let's talk about tailoring the processes.
First off there are four key facts that we need to know.
The first one is what processes are we going to use on the project.
So I know I don't have to use all the processes but which ones should I use or will we be using in this
project.
The second one is to what depth.
So if we know we have to do a managed quality process.
But what does that mean exactly to what depth to what extent or we're going to do risk analysis of qualitative
and quantitative risk analysis to what depth if it's a large high profile project.
Typically I'm going to go deeper and more intense in those processes.
A small low priority project pretty high level I don't either invest a lot of time at all these processes.
So depending what the project is the priority of the project and the process that we selected will make
a determination as to how intense to what depth to what extent do we do that process.
We already know Step 3 Not every process is needed on every project.
So that's a given.
Now we've got that down.
Typically though Step 4 The larger the project the more processes are likely.
So the bigger the project probably you're going to touch a lot more processes than a small project.
A few more things about tailoring in the Pinback guy throughout the Pinback I will see this idea of
tailoring a process or tailoring processes and these will be in the different knowledge areas chapters
starting in chapter 4 on integration management all the way to 13 on stakeholder management.
So what we'll see here Step 1 will be knowledge areas.
So each knowledge area will be some tailoring that can happen.
We know processes step to here processes live inside of knowledge areas and then step three Tailleur
those to fit your project.
So it's the project the priority the project the characteristics of the project that will tell us which
processes we need and to what extent do we need those processes and then Step Number four the fourth
thing to know throughout the Pinback guide as I mentioned we'll see an opportunity to do tailoring.
So just be aware that don't let that throw us.
We knew through these chapters and tailoring comes back again every knowledge area every process has
an opportunity to be tailored.
All right I'll see you in the next lecture.